<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">
    <string name="app_name">Arrived</string>
    <string name="AboutUs">Arrived is a <EMAIL mailto="william@arrived.us">team</EMAIL> project.\n\nFor more information, including ways to contact us to provide feedback, you can visit <a href="http://www.arrived.us">our website</a>.\n\n\"When we arrive, sons and daughters, we\'ll make our homes on the water...\"</string>
    <string name="copyright" translatable="false">© 2016</string>
    <string name="learnButton">Learn</string>
    <string name="seeButton">See</string>
    <string name="sharing_header">You can share answers with others!</string>
    <string name="sharing_text_message">Hey! Arrived has helped me and I would like you to use it, too. www.arrived.us</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu1">Immigration Reform/DACA/Trump Plans 2017</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu2">Visa Help</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu3">Housing</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu4">Job Assistance</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu5">Legal Section</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu6">Deportation Help</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu7">Education</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu8">Support Groups</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu9">FAQ</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu10">About Us</string>
    <string name="gettingStarted">First of all, thank you for installing Arrived.\n\nThis app helps you make your home in the US no matter where you are from or how you arrived. In the app, you will find info, advice, and commentary about the US immigration process. You can find housing tips, common legal questions, and even links to English language lessons.\n\nNo matter how you arrived in the US, we want to make sure you can make a smooth transition. We hope this app comes in handy—we’ve had fun making it and we hope you have fun using it!\n\nLastly, if you’d like to request new features, provide helpful information, or share your story, we’d love to hear from you. You can see all the ways to contact us <a href="http://www.arrived.us/contact.html">here</a>.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion1">What is a visa?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer1">A visa is a document that lets you travel to, live in, or work in a country.
        In the US, there are two types of visas—immigrant and non-immigrant—that serve different purposes.
        \n\nThe Department of State is responsible for deciding who receives visas.
        You can apply for both types of visas at US embassies around the world.
        \n&#8226;Immigrant Visas: People wishing to immigrate to the United States.
        \n&#8226;Non-Immigrant visas: People wishing to visit for business or tourism, study at a school or university,
        or receive medical treatment in the US.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion2">Do I need a visa?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer2">US law requires you to have some form of documentation if you are in the country. If you do not have a visa or if you have overstayed your visa, you are considered an undocumented immigrant. Undocumented immigrants cannot vote, receive benefits, or have American passports. If you are an undocumented immigrant, however, and you do not commit a crime, authorities are unlikely to know you are here.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion3">What are the penalties for overstaying a visa or entering the country illegally?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer3">If you enter the US without passing through a border control post or if you provide false documents, you can face six months to two years in prison. If you are caught while crossing the border, you may go to an immigration detention center. You will then face an Immigration Court that will decide whether to deport you. If you are deported, it may hurt your chances of receiving a visa in the future.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion4">How can I receive a green card?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer4">You must be here with documents to receive a green card. If you are here without documents, you must secure a visa through your family, employer, military service, or university. Once you have a visa, you may begin the green card application process. It is difficult if not impossible to obtain a green card without legal status.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion5">How can I secure a green card through my family?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer5">If you have an American relative, you may be able to receive a visa. If you have an immediate relative in the US, you can apply for a visa and receive special priority. In particular, spouses of permanent residents, unmarried children under the age of 21, and parents of the permanent resident may “skip the line” for a visa.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion6">How can I receive a green card through marriage?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer6">If your spouse is an American, he or she can file for you to receive a green card and you will receive the visa immediately if you are eligible. You must marry within 90 days of entering the US and you and your fiancé are both eligible to marry each other.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion7">How can I receive a visa through my employer?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer7">If an employer has a high-skilled job that the US government decides it cannot fill with American workers, it may allow the employer to sponsor your visa. These high-skilled jobs must not displace an American worker, and the number of slots is capped. This visa requires a job offer so you cannot apply for a work visa without one.  \"</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion8">How can I receive a visa through my school?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer8">There are two types of visas for students: F-1 and M-1. You must be enrolled full-time in a language, vocational, or educational program approved by the USCIS. Importantly, you must be able to support yourself and intend to return home after your studies end.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion9">How can I receive a visa for military service?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer9">Those who honorably serve in the US Armed Services can apply for citizenship provided that they are at least 18 years old; can read, write, and speak English; and have lived in the US for five years and in the US for at least 30 months out of the past five years before the time of the application.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion10">How can I apply for refugee status?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer10">A refugee is someone who flees violence in his or her home country or who has reasonable fear of violence or persecution. If you are admitted to the US as a refugee or asylum seeker, you can apply for refugee status one year after arrival.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion11">How can I become a US citizen?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer11">The process of becoming a citizen is called naturalization.\nFive years after arrival, if you demonstrate knowledge of the English language and US history and government, you can obtain citizenship. If you marry an American, this waiting period is shortened to three years as long as you have been married for three years.\nThe advantages of citizenship over permanent residency include assisting relatives immigrate to the US and voting in elections.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion12">How can I avoid visa scams?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer12">\n1)	Ask questions\n2)	Ask for documentation showing the person is licensed or bonded\n3)	Demand a written contract for immigration services\n4)	Get copies of the papers prepared for you\n5)	Get a receipt with amount paid, the date, and name and address of person or business\n6)	Get a second opinion\n7)	Make sure the immigration consultant or immigration attorney signs your forms as the preparer\nAttention! You should never\n1)	Trust an immigration consultant or public notary just because a friend invites you to meet them\n2)	Pay for entire services before signing a contract or before work is complete\n3)	Sign blank application papers\n4)	Sign papers, immigration forms, or contracts that you do not fully understand\n5)	Let anyone keep your original documents\n6)	Pay for government application forms. Form are free and can be downloaded via <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/forms">this page</a>.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion13">What is the difference between an immigration consultant and lawyer?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer13">A consultant is not the same as a lawyer. A consultant undergoes a background check and pays a fee to become licensed. He or she can answer questions on immigration forms, provide copies, submit forms, and translate questions and answers. They cannot get you visas or work permits immediately or influence government officials.\nA lawyer, on the other hand, can provide legal advice, advise which forms you will need, assist with your immigration case, and represent you in court.</string>
    <string name="housingQuestion1">How can I find housing in my area that is safe, affordable, and available?</string>
    <string name="housingAnswer1">Finding safe and comfortable housing is one of the hardest problems new immigrants face in the United States.In general, you can find housing on <a href="http://www.craigslist.com">Craigslist</a> (you can change the city on the site when you search).In addition, you can find a local newspaper and read the “Classifieds” section—it usually contains available apartments or home for rent.Lastly, you can go to <a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a> and search for “rental housing + city name” on your phone to view other local websites.Many Americans also find housing by looking for signs that say “For Rent” in the neighborhood.\n\nIf you feel as if you may qualify for public housing because of your income level, you can find contact information for your local Public Housing Agency <a href="http://portal.hud.gov/hudportal/HUD?src=/program_offices/public_indian_housing/pha/contacts">here</a>.More information about specific state programs that provide housing assistance to those in need can be found <a href="http://portal.hud.gov/hudportal/HUD?src=/topics/rental_assistance/local">here</a>.
    </string>
    <string name="housingQuestion2">What rights do I have as a renter in general in the US?</string>
    <string name="housingAnswer2">Many laws vary by state—for a complete list of tenant rights for your state, you can visit <a href="http://portal.hud.gov/hudportal/HUD?src=/topics/rental_assistance/tenantrights">this site</a>. The Fair Housing Act protects people from discrimination when they are renting, buying, or securing financing for any housing. It also bans discrimination based on nationality. Landlords cannot set different prices for renters or refuse to negotiate for housing based on nationality.
        \n\nYou should check if you state has standard residential leases. In these states, such as California, you should check that the lease you sign matches the standard one.
        \n\nIf you feel as if you have faced discrimination in your housing search, you can and should file a complaint within one year. You can submit a HUD form <a href="http://www.hud.gov/complaints/housediscrim.cfm">here</a> that starts an investigation into the alleged violation. If the government finds discrimination did occur, you can receive money for damages as well as the right to live in the housing. You can find more information about the Fair Housing Act and your rights under that law <a href="http://portal.hud.gov/hudportal/HUD?src=/program_offices/fair_housing_equal_opp/FHLaws/yourrights">here</a>.
    </string>
    <string name="housingQuestion3">What can I do if my landlord is taking advantage of me?</string>
    <string name="housingAnswer3">You should contact a Housing Counseling Agency in your state. A list of Housing Counseling Agencies is <a href="http://www.hud.gov/offices/hsg/sfh/hcc/hcs.cfm">here</a>.An agent provides advice on buying a home, renting, defaults, foreclosures, and credit issues. You can also call (800) 569-4287 for free.\n\nFor more information about security deposit fraud, you can visit <a href="http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/security-deposit-limits-deadlines-your-state-36186.html">this website</a> for state-specific information.
    </string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion1">What are some common job-searching websites?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer1">Immigrants report that finding a job can be one of the hardest steps when arriving in the US. You can search for employment on websites, at local community centers, or at local businesses in your area.
    \n\n1) On <a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a>, you can search for jobs by entering your local area (i.e., “Boston” or “Miami”) followed by a job title.
    \n\n2) <a href="http://www.monster.com/">Monster</a> is one of the largest career websites in the US. It displays job opportunities for most of the largest companies as well as many small and medium businesses. You first create your profile on the website and then search by job title and location.
    \n\n3) <a href="http://www.craigslist.org">Craigslist</a> organizes itself by geography: you first pick your city and then you can view job placements. Many of the jobs on Craigslist are temporary, but you can also find longer-term jobs there as well.
    \n\n4) <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/">LinkedIn</a> is a free and popular social media website for professionals. You can create a profile, enter your skills and prior jobs, and search for open opportunities. The site has search features that let you pick a location and an industry as well as type of company. You can also message companies and other users directly.</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion2">What are some other ways to find a job?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer2">1)	Talk to friends, relatives, and other recent arrivals to the US. They can put you in touch with businesses who may not advertise a job listing or who do not advertise online. Networking is a common way to find a job in the US.\n\n2)	Approach local businesses in person. You can also search <a href="http://www.maps.google.com">Google Maps</a> for local businesses. Then you make a list of each business’ hours, address, and type. It’s best to go to these businesses when they are not busy (typically 30min after open and 30min before close). Ask to speak with the manager and bring a friend if you are not at ease speaking English yet. Be sure to bring a copy of your resume if you have one (and see the section in this app about resume writing!). An in-person visit helps more than a resume drop off or online application.
    </string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion3">How do I write a resume?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer3"><a href="http://www.arrived.us/sample_resume_1.html">Sample resume 1</a>\n\n<a href="http://www.arrived.us/sample_resume_2.html">Sample resume 2</a>
    </string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion4">I was discriminated at work. Is discrimination against the law?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer4">Discrimination at work based on age, skin color, nationality, and religion is undocumented. Your employer also has an obligation to stop any harassment from co-workers due to your race, nationality, or religion. Your employer also cannot treat you differently because of your accent. You cannot be hired or fired because of your religion, skin color, or nationality, and employers may not retaliate against you if you file a discrimination claim. If you feel as if you have been discriminated, write down the facts of the case and contact the <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/contact/index.cfm">U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)</a>.</string>
    <string name="legalHelpQuestion1">Where can I find legal help?</string>
    <string name="legalHelpAnswer1">Many local, state, and national organizations can help you tackle immigration problems. You can begin with a search on <a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a> for immigrant legal center followed by your city name. Some of these organizations will provide support but not legal counsel; others will provide free legal services or put you in touch with law clinics. You can also search for “voluntary,” “civil rights lawyer,” or “immigration law clinic OR caucus” to find an organization that can help you. Local law schools at universities may also have students who can provide legal assistance.
    </string>
    <string name="legalHelpQuestion2">How do I know I can trust an organization?</string>
    <string name="legalHelpAnswer2">You should ask each organization for a list of partner organizations. Most non-profits have connections with other local or national non-profits. In addition, you should ask if they could put you in touch with past clients.</string>
    <string name="legalHelpQuestion3">I have an immigration appeal. Which organization can provide services for me?</string>
    <string name="legalHelpAnswer3">
        You should find an organization recognized by the Board of Immigration Appeals (BIA). For an organization to be recognized, it must have enough knowledge and experience to provide services to immigrants. A recognized organization can charge or accept only very small fees for those services. For a list of these BIA-recognized organizations, visit <a href="http://www.justice.gov/eoir/recognition-accreditationroster-reports">www.justice.gov/eoir/recognition-accreditationroster-reports</a>.
        \n\n•	An Accredited Representative: People who are connected to BIA recognized organizations. These representatives can charge or accept only very small fees for their services. For a list of these BIA-accredited representatives, visit <a href="http://www.justice.gov/eoir/recognition-accreditationroster-reports">http://www.justice.gov/eoir/recognition-accreditationroster-reports</a>.
        \n\n•	A Qualified Representative: People who will provide free services. These representatives must know about immigration law and the rules of practice in court. Law school students and graduates, and people with good moral character who have a personal or professional affiliation with you (relative, neighbor, clergy, co-worker, or friend) are all examples of qualified representatives.
        \n\n•	Free Legal Service Providers: The Department of Justice has a list of recognized free legal service providers for people who are in immigration proceedings. This is a list of attorneys and organizations that may be willing to represent immigrants in proceedings before immigration courts. The attorneys and organizations on this list have agreed to help immigrants pro bono (free of charge) only in immigration proceedings. Some of them may not be able to help you with non-court-related matters, such as visa petitions, naturalization, etc. The list is available at <a href="www.justice.gov/eoir/free-legal-services-providers">www.justice.gov/eoir/free-legal-services-providers</a>.
        \n\n•	Pro Bono Program: Local lists of recognized pro bono organizations and their representatives are usually available at each local USCIS office. For more information about finding legal services, please visit <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/legaladvice">USCIS</a>.
    </string>
    <string name="legalHelpQuestion4">What should I do when I encounter the police, immigration, or customs agents?</string>
    <string name="legalHelpAnswer4">
        •	You have to give your name and date of birth—nothing else
        \n\n\•	You do not need to answer any other questions
        \n\n•	You have the right to talk to a lawyer first and receive interpretation services
        \n\n•	Agents may not enter your home without a warrant
        \n\n•	While agents can pat you down, they cannot perform a wider search
        \n\n•	You should neither sign any documents without a lawyer present nor present any false documents
        \n\n•	Record the agent’s name and ID

        \n\nHere is a sample conversation with phrases you should use:
        \n\n\1.	“I choose to remain silent.”
        \n\n2.	“I need {Spanish/Portuguese/Chinese…} language help.”
        \n\n3.	“Am I free to leave?”
        \n\na.	If no: “I would like to speak to a lawyer”
        \n\nb.	If yes: Leave immediately
        \n\n4.	“I want to contact this (organization/attorney) at this (phone number).”
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion1">What to do if Immigrations and Customs Enforcement arrests you?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer1">
        •	Ask for a lawyer and stay quiet. Only state your name and date of birth.
        \n\n•	Always give your complete and true name.
        \n\n•	Call family and ask them to find you a lawyer.
        \n\n•	Do not sign any papers without consulting a lawyer.
        \n\n•	You will be assigned an “A Number.” Write it down and share it with your family.
        \n\n•	Ask for a bond.
        \n\n•	Write down who is arresting you and their ID numbers.
        \n\n•	Asked to be released on bond. If it is denied, ask for a bond hearing before a judge.
        \n\n•	If you are given an electronic ankle bracelet for tracking, you can file a challenge with the immigration court within seven days of your release.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion2">What do I need to know about posting bond?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer2">
        Posting bond means you go to a prison or jail and pay money to release an inmate. This money is returned to you if the inmate arrives at his or her court appearance (typically 1-3 months after the initial detention). In some cases, you cannot post bond.
        \n\nMost people are eligible for bond unless they have a history of serious criminal convictions. If you have illegally re-entered after deportation may not get bond either. However, if you have been in custody for over six months, you may request bond no matter your criminal or deportation past. Once bond is posted, you will be released and required to appear before a judge in deportation or removal hearings at a later date.

    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion3">How can I post bond?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer3">
        You can call the DHS Detention and Deportation branch and give the person’s name, date of birth, date of arrest, and number. You can then ask if the bond has been set and the steps to pay it. To post bond, you must be a citizen or legal resident of the United States. By posting bond, you accept responsibility for that person presenting him- or herself before a deportation official. They may run a background check on the payer, so you may wish to consult an attorney beforehand. When the case is complete, you will receive the money back assuming the person has complied with the ruling and does not attempt to flee.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion4">What is a deportation proceeding?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer4">
        Removal Proceedings are a series of hearings in immigration court overseen by an immigration judge. An attorney at the hearing will represent both the Department of Homeland Security and Immigration and Customs Enforcement. Unlike a criminal proceeding, the government will not provide a lawyer for you. The consequences for not appearing at a court hearing are severe. There are two types of hearings: master and individual. Master hearings are shorter whereas individual hearings are longer and let you plead your case. A decision is not typically made at your first hearing.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion5">What is cancellation of removal?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer5">
        Cancellation of Removal is a ruling for those without status to prevent their deportation. In order to be eligible for cancellation of removal, you must be a person of good character, a resident in the US for 10 years before the removal proceedings began, and a law-abiding individual free of criminal charges. In addition, if your removal would case grave harm to a US resident or citizen, you may be able to receive a cancellation of removal.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion6">What is temporary protected status?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer6">
        Temporary Protected Status (TPS) is a status for foreign nationals in the US whose home countries are unsafe. You cannot renew TPS if you have been convicted of a crime. You cannot leave the US with TPS without prior permission.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion7">What is adjustment of status?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer7">
        Adjustment of Status (AOS) is a procedure that allows for an individual to apply for lawful permanent resident status without leaving the US. Either your family or your employer can file the petition to grant you AOS. However, if you are in the US without documents, you may not be able to adjust status even with a petition.
    </string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion8">What are my constitutional rights?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer8">
        If immigration agents or local police arrested you illegally, you may be able to challenge the evidence against you in immigration court. Immigrants still have constitutional rights, and agents must respect those rights.
    </string>
    <string name="englishHelpQuestion1">What are some ways to learn English online?</string>
    <string name="englishHelpAnswer1">
        These websites will help you learn English online:
        \n\n• The Carlos Slim Foundation created an Android/iOS app called <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.aprende.app&amp;utm_source=aprende.org&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_content=aprende.org_badge&amp;utm_campaign=PartBadge&amp;pcampaignid=aprende.org_badge">apprende.org</a> that teaches you everyday English for your job. You can study vocabulary and terms in different areas including arts and culture, health, and work-related fields. It’s free to download and use, and many immigrants have rated it highly.
        \n\n•	<a href="http://www.usalearns.org/">USA Learns</a>. The US government created a website that teaches English for free online. It is aimed for beginners and intermediate learners.
        \n\n•	BBC. The British television broadcaster created <a href="http://www.usalearns.org/">free English lessons</a> you can use online. These materials will teach you pronunciation and everyday English. It is best for those with some knowledge of English already.
        \n\n•	Pronunciation. Many who study English find that pronouncing words is one of the hardest parts of learning the language. <a href="http://www.manythings.org/pp/">This website</a> provides “listen and repeat” exercises for common sounds.
        \n\n•	TV. Television is an excellent way to learn English. You can start by watching TV in English with English sub-titles. At first, many of the words will be confusing. But if you keep a dictionary near you and look up words as you see them, you will find that you can slowly build a strong vocabulary.
        \n\n•	Blogs. You can also read blogs to learn English. <a href="http://eslhiphop.com/">ESL Hip Hop</a> takes its inspiration from influential hip hop/rap songs to teach everything from prepositions to tenses.
        \n\n•	Apps. The Play Store has many apps that teach English. The British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) launched a <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vn.scdgroup.bbclearningenglish">conversational English app</a> with quick six-minute lessons. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hk.hkbc.epodcast">LearnEnglish Podcasts</a> is a perfect app for slightly more advanced students—its episodes feature native speakers discussing their hobbies, weekend plans, and activities and a highlighted script you can read while listening. Lastly, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.duolingo">DuoLingo</a> is a popular app among Americans learning a foreign language; its English-language version builds vocabulary and grammar via fun, fast games and daily challenges.
        \n\n•	Dictionaries. <a href="http://www.wordreference.org/">WordReference</a> and <a href="http://www.babelfish.com/">BabelFish</a> are two online dictionaries for English-Spanish and Spanish-English translation.</string>
    <string name="englishHelpQuestion2">How can I learn common phrases in English along with their meanings?</string>
    <string name="englishHelpAnswer2">
        Idioms are short phrases that you will encounter when speaking or reading English. These expressions are incredibly helpful to convey an idea, but they often are nonsensical when read at first. <a href="http://www.smart-words.org/quotes-sayings/idioms-meaning.html">This website</a> provides an explanation of common idioms in English. If you feel confident in your English already, you can study these idioms and begin to use them in conversation. Once you start to learn them, you will start to hear these expressions frequently!
    </string>
    <string name="supportGroupsQuestion1">What support groups are open to me as a documented/undocumented immigrant?</string>
    <string name="supportGroupsAnswer1">
        The US has many local, state, and national groups that cater to immigrants from all backgrounds. PublicEye.org keeps a thorough list <a href="http://www.publiceye.org/research/directories/immig_grp_defend.html">here</a>. You can also find more groups <a href="http://www.nnirr.org/drupal/border-groups">here</a> thanks to the National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights.
    </string>

    <string name="faqQuestion1">How can I share this app with my friends?</string>
    <string name="faqAnswer1">You can share this app by clicking on the icon on the top right corner of the page.</string>
    <string name="faqQuestion2">Help! I need a lawyer. Could you please refer me?</string>
    <string name="faqAnswer2">
        Unfortunately, we cannot provide legal advice or refer you to an attorney. However, you can find a lawyer in your area who can assist with your specific case with Google, through referrals from friends or relatives, or at a local library’s law section. In addition, the Department of Justice has a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/eoir/list-pro-bono-legal-service-providers-map">list</a> of free legal service providers by state. It also has a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/eoir/recognition-accreditation-roster-reports">database</a> of accredited or trustworthy organizations that provide legal services to immigrants.
    </string>
    <string name="updates">You\'re holding the first version of our app! We hope you like it.</string>
    <string name="eula">Arrived End User License Agreement
        \n\n
        This End User License Agreement (“EULA”) is a legal agreement between the end-user Customer of Arrived’s Software Products (“Customer”) and Arrived (“Arrived”) regarding Customer’s use of the Software (as defined below).  Arrived is willing to license the Software to Customer upon the condition that it accepts and complies with the terms contained in this EULA where Customer accepts such license at the time of download of the EULA, the (“Agreement”).
        Customer’s use, installation, or access of the Software constitutes agreement with and acceptance of this Agreement.
        \n\n 	Definitions.
        \n\na.  “Software” means the object or binary code or firmware, any accompanying documentation, and any upgrades or updates therefor, that are provided by Arrived or an Approved Source on Arrived’s behalf, and either are (i) included with or embedded in the Arrived Hardware, or (ii) provided as a stand-alone software product. For the avoidance of doubt, Software expressly excludes third party software.
        \n\nb.  “Hardware” means the hardware products, purchased from Arrived directly or through an authorized Arrived channel partner (“Approved Source”) that may include Software and expressly excludes third party non-Arrived branded hardware products that may run Software.
        \n\nc. “Product” means, the Software, the Hardware, and/or any combination thereof.
        \n\n
        \n\nLicense Grant. Subject to and conditioned upon Customer’s compliance with the restrictions and terms set forth in the Agreement:
        \n\nArrived hereby grants Customer a non-exclusive, non-sublicensable, non-transferable worldwide license to (i) use the Software for Customer’s personal purposes or educational purposes only; and (ii) Customer may install and use an unlimited number of copies of the Software but shall not charge a fee for distributing this Software (either for profit or merely to recover media and distribution costs).
        \n\n
        Restrictions. Arrived Software is being distributed without a fee.  Customer will not, nor will he or she allow or authorize any third party to:
        \n\na. copy, duplicate, disclose, distribute, modify, sublicense, license, transfer, or exploit or create derivative works of the Software or permit any third party to do so for profit without prior written consent of Arrived, it’s owners, agents or representatives;
        \n\nb. use, transfer, or distribute the Software in competition with Arrived;
        \n\nc. decompile, reverse translate, disassemble, or reverse engineer the Software or cause the Software to be subject to any open source obligations or release;
        \n\nd. remove any proprietary markings or copyright notices from any Arrived Software, or translate the Software into any other format or language without prior written consent of Arrived, it’s owners, agents or representatives.
        \n\n
        \n\nCopyright. The license granted in this Agreement is not a transfer or sale of Arrived or its licensors’ ownership rights in the Software or its intellectual property. Except for the license specifically granted in this Agreement, Arrived retains all right, title, and interest in and to the Software, the related source code and intellectual property, and any and all modifications or derivatives. The Software is confidential to Arrived and protected by applicable trade secret and intellectual property laws. Arrived owns all title and copyrights of the Software Product.  The Software Product is protected by copyright laws and international treaty provisions.
        \n\n
        \n\nTechnical Support. For ninety (90) days from the date the Software is downloaded by the Customer or shipped to the Customer by Arrived or an Approved Source, Arrived may ¬provide software updates (bug fixes, maintenance releases, and feature upgrades) for the Software.
        \n\nNo Other Warranties. EXCEPT AS SET FORTH HEREIN, THE PRODUCT IS PROVIDED ON AN “AS IS” BASIS. CUSTOMER ASSUMES ALL RESPONSIBILITIES FOR SELECTION OF THE PRODUCT TO ACHIEVE ITS INTENDED RESULTS, AND FOR THE INSTALLATION OF, USE OF, AND RESULTS OBTAINED.  ARRIVED MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS AND UNDERTAKES NO INDEMNIFICATION OBLIGATIONS REGARDING, ARISING FROM, OR RELATED TO THE LEGALITY OF MONITORING OF NETWORKS OR INFORMATION IN A PARTICULAR JURISDICTION, AND CUSTOMER IS SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR DETERMINING THAT CUSTOMER’S PROPOSED OR ACTUAL USE OF THE PRODUCT COMPLIES WITH APPLICABLE LAWS. CUSTOMER ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT ARRIVED WILL HAVE NO LIABILITY WHATSOEVER FOR ANY CLAIMS, LOSSES, ACTIONS, DAMAGES, SUITS, OR PROCEEDINGS RESULTING FROM: (A) THE USE OF THE PRODUCTS BY CUSTOMER OR THIRD PARTIES.  COMMUNICATION OF INFORMATION BY, IN, TO OR THROUGH THE SOFTWARE PRODUCT AND CUSTOMER’S RECEIPT OR USE OF IT (1) IS NOT INTENDED TO CONVEY OR CONSTITUTE LEGAL ADVICE, AND (2) IS NOT A SUBSTITUTE FOR OBTAINING LEGAL ADVICE FROM A QUALIFIED ATTORNEY.  CUSTOMER SHOULD NOT ACT UPON ANY SUCH INFORMATION WITHOUT FIRST SEEKING QUALIFIED PROFESSIONAL COUNSEL ON HIS OR HER SPECIFIC MATTER.
        \n\nTerm and Termination. This Agreement is effective as of the date of Customer’s first use or access, or installation of the Software and remains in effect until Customer’s failure to comply with any term of this Agreement, including any failure to pay license fees, if applicable. In such event Customer must destroy all copies of the Software Product and all of its component parts.
        \n\n
        Limitation of Liability. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES WILL ARRIVED (including its officers, employees, directors, subsidiaries, representatives, affiliates, agents, contributors and licensors) BE LIABLE FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES WHATSOEVER ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE PRODUCTS, EVEN IF ARRIVED HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
        \n\nIndemnification. Customer will defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Arrived (including its officers, employees, directors, subsidiaries, representatives, affiliates, agents, contributors and licensors) from and against any damages (including reasonable attorney’s fees and expenses), claims, and lawsuits that arise or result from Customer’s breach of any provision of this Agreement.
        \n\n
        Intellectual Property. Arrived, its logo, and all other names, logos, or icons identifying Arrived and its programs, products, and services are proprietary, and any use of identical or confusingly similar marks, including as domain names, without Arrived’s express written permission is strictly prohibited.
        Jurisdiction. This Agreement is governed by the laws of the State of California, without reference to its conflict of laws principles. Except as set forth above, any dispute regarding this Agreement will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the state and federal courts located in San Francisco County,  California, U.S.A. This Agreement is the entire agreement between Customer and Arrived and supersedes any other communications with respect to the Software.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="startingButton">Start</string>
    <string name="aboutButton">About</string>
    <string name="englishHelpQuestion3">What is the Dream Act and how can I benefit?</string>
    <string name="englishHelpAnswer3">The DREAM Act (acronym for Development, Relief, and Education for Alien Minors) is an American legislative proposal for a multi-phase process for undocumented immigrants in the United States that would first grant conditional residency and upon meeting further qualifications, permanent residency.</string>
    <string name="englishHelpQuestion4">If I am an undocumented immigrant, can I enroll my children in public school?</string>
    <string name="englishHelpAnswer4">All children in the United States are entitled to equal access to a basic public elementary and secondary education regardless of their actual or perceived race, color, national origin, citizenship, immigration status, or the status of their parents/guardians. School districts that either prohibit or discourage, or maintain policies that have the effect of prohibiting or discouraging, children from enrolling in schools because they or their parents/guardians are not U.S. citizens or are undocumented may be in violation of Federal law.</string>
    <string name="englishHelpQuestion5">What is Khan Academy?</string>
    <string name="englishHelpAnswer5">Khan Academy is a personalized learning resource for all ages. Khan Academy offers practice exercises, instructional videos, and a personalized learning dashboard that empower learners to study at their own pace in and outside of the classroom. It teaches math, science, computer programming, history, art history, economics, and more.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer14">A consulate is an office of one nation located in the country of another. For example, at the Mexican consulate in San Francisco, diplomats work to represent Mexicans living in the US with paperwork, advice, and even legal visitation if they are arrested. The grounds of a consulate do not belong to the host country. So the Mexican consulate in San Francisco is part of Mexico—not the United States. A Consul General is the head of the office. Consulates can be found in major cities of a country, but typically not the capital of a country.  \n\n An embassy, on the other hand, is located in the capital of a country. An ambassador oversees the office. It performs many of the same duties as the consulate but on a larger scale.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion14">What are consulate and an embassy?</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu12">Driving</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion5">I am a victim of labor trafficking. What can I do now that I have arrived in the US?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer5">Labor trafficking is a form of slavery that occurs when someone is taken from his or her home, smuggled to a new place, and forced to work. But labor trafficking can take other forms as well: debt bondage, coercion, and even child labor. Certain industries such as agriculture, hospitality, and manufacturing employ more trafficked individuals than others.\n\nIf you have been forced, defrauded, or coerced into working, you can call the National Human Trafficking Resource Center (1-888-373-7888) 24 hours a day, seven days a week, for free to speak to someone who can help you.\n\nIn 2000, the US government enacted a new law to protect victims of trafficking. Benefits include educational, health care, job training, and other state or federal programs that refugees receive in the US. In addition, victims may be eligible for the witness protection program.\n\nIn addition, the law created the T Visa that allows victims of severe forms of trafficking and their immediate family members to become temporary residents of the US.</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceQuestion6">What are my rights as an undocumented worker in the United States?</string>
    <string name="careerGuidanceAnswer6">Undocumented workers enjoy all of the legal rights provided by both federal and state law.\n\nSo the same Federal and California wage and hour laws that apply to authorized workers generally apply to persons working without legal immigration status. These laws establish your right to minimum wage, overtime pay, breaks, tips, and other forms of wages. For example, an employer cannot refuse to pay you by saying that you should not have been working in the first place because you have no “papers.”\n\nIf you choose to file a wage claim, you can either file with the California Division of Labor Standards Enforcement (the “Labor Commissioner”) or sue your employer in court. You can also contact the U.S. Department of Labor (DOL). Neither of these agencies should question you about your immigration status.\n\nHowever, if you do report your employer, he may retaliate against you by contacting immigration authorities who may deport you.</string>
    <string name="drivingQuestion1">How can I receive a driver’s license?</string>
    <string name="drivingAnswer1">If you are an immigrant in the US who has documentation, you can apply for a driver’s licenses at your state’s Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV). You will typically need to bring proof of your identity and an original copy of your driving permit from your home country. If you are an undocumented immigrant, certain states will let you take a driver’s test and receive a license. California, Colorado, Connecticut, Illinois, Maryland, New Mexico, Nevada, Utah, Vermont and Washington D.C., and Washington allow it. To apply for a license in these states, follow the advice at the bottom of <a href="http://accesolatino.org/licencias/">this page</a>.</string>
    <string name="drivingQuestion2">What do I do if a police officer stops my car?</string>
    <string name="drivingAnswer2">1.	Slow down safely and park beside the road without blocking traffic.\n\n2.	Lower the driver’s side window.\n\n3.	Keep your hands on the steering wheel.\n\n4.	Do not reach in your pocket or to the glove compartment—the officer will assume you are reaching for a gun.\n\n5.	Say as little as possible and politely end sentences with “officer” or “sir.”\n\n6.	If an officer tries to search your body or car, you can say, “Officer, I’m not resisting. I do not consent to this search.” \n\n7.	Never touch or physically resist a police officer.</string>
    <string name="drivingQuestion3">How can I be a safe driver?</string>
    <string name="drivingAnswer3">You should always obey the speed limit and street signs, especially in school zones and cities. Remember that in the US, turn signals and street lines are rules not suggestions, and drivers are often distracted with cell phones and meals while behind the wheel. In the US, most intersections have crosswalks and although you may be tempted to pull up to the white line, you may hit or block pedestrians crossing the street.</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu14">Health Knowledge</string>
    <string name="healthQuestion1">How can I purchase health insurance?</string>
    <string name="healthAnswer1">With the Affordable Care Act (ACA), you are required to sign up for healthcare insurance if you live in the US as a citizen or documented immigrant. If you do not purchase insurance, you will have to pay a fine.
        \n\nIf you are an undocumented immigrant or incarcerated, you are not eligible to sign up for the healthcare exchanges. You will not be charged a penalty for failing to purchase health insurance. In addition, undocumented immigrants are not eligible for federal coverage including Medicare and non-emergency Medicaid.
        \n\nHealth care plans vary by state, so you can’t compare plans across state lines. Some states provide limited free medical service regardless of immigration status (such as <a href="https://www.medi-cal.ca.gov/">Medi-Cal</a> in California), so you should check if your state has a similar program. The cheapest health care option for immigrant families who do not purchase health insurance is a community health center. A directory of community health centers is <a href="https://findahealthcenter.hrsa.gov/index.html">here</a>. At these health centers, you pay what you can afford.</string>
    <string name="healthQuestion2">If I am sick and go to a hospital and can’t afford it, what happens next?</string>
    <string name="healthAnswer2">You have a few options: make sure the charges on the bill are correct; ask if the hospital will draft an interest-free payment plan; ask for an on-time pay discount; and apply for financial assistance. If you still cannot afford the bills, you can file for Chapter 7 bankruptcy (if your income is below the median income for your state) or Chapter 13 (and allow the hospital to deduct your wages until the bill is repaid).</string>
    <string name="healthQuestion3">How can I purchase healthy food at a low price?</string>
    <string name="healthAnswer3">In the US, many restaurants and supermarkets offer unhealthy yet cheap food. You can go to membership supermarkets such as Costco and Sam’s Club to purchase food in bulk at discounted prices. In addition, you should see if your town has a farmer’s market where you can purchase fruits and vegetables at lower prices than a local supermarket.</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu15">Financial Advice</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion1">How can I open a bank account?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer1">Many banks in the US let you open a bank account for free. There are two types of accounts: checking and savings. A checking account gives the account holder a book of checks that some businesses accept instead of cash. These accounts do not earn interest. A savings account, on the other hand, will give you a debit card and allow you to earn a small interest rate. The main banks in the US are Bank of America, Chase, Wells Fargo, TD Bank, and Citi Bank.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion2">How can I sign up for a credit card?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer2">You need a credit score to sign up for a credit card. A credit score is a rating that predicts how likely you are to repay your debts. A high credit score is 850 and 200 is a low credit score. You can start a credit score by applying for a secured credit card. If you make payments each month and do not spend over the limit, your credit score will increase over time.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion3">I need to file for taxes. How can I pay them?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer3">Each April, Americans pay taxes to the federal, state, and local governments. Both TurboTax and VITA can help you file for taxes for free. Many individuals qualify for free tax preparation from TurboTax.
        \n\n<a href="https://turbotax.intuit.com/personal-taxes/online/free-edition.jsp">TurboTax</a> is a software program that calculates how much you owe in federal and state taxes if applicable. Typically, Americans pay taxes every April. If you earn less than $100,000 and you have standard deductions, you can file for free with the TurboTax Federal Free Edition.
        \n\nVITA is a government service to individuals earning less than $54,000 per year or taxpayers with limited English. IRS-certified volunteers will prepare your tax return at a community center near you. You can find VITA locations <a href="https://irs.treasury.gov/freetaxprep/">here</a>.
        \n\n\If you are self-employed or you work at home, you may be able to deduct car, rent, equipment, and other costs from your tax bill. You should check which deductions apply to you.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion4">What is a loan shark and how do I avoid them?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer4">A loan shark offers short-term loans at high interest rates. In the US, these lenders are also known as payday lending companies. Many states have set maximum interest rates that you can offer for a loan (typically below 50%). Several states have rules that limit the number of rollovers allowed. So if you live in Texas, the payday lender cannot rollover the debt into the next period (and increase the total amount owed).</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion5">How can I track my income and expenses with an app or online?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer5">Several apps can track your income and expenses. <a href="http://www.mint.com">Mint</a> is a popular website and app that is free to use. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dayspringtech.envelopes">GoodBudget</a> is another app for Android and iOS that lets you set a budget and measure your performance. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.blodhgard.easybudget">Fast Budget</a> is an app that merges your credit card spending with your bank account activity.</string>
    <string name="legalHelpQuestion5">What is a public defender?</string>
    <string name="legalHelpAnswer5">In the US, every individual has a right to a lawyer if convicted of a crime. If you are convicted of a crime but cannot afford an attorney, the court will appoint a public defender (a government official) to represent you in court. These public defenders will take your side in a case and attempt to dismiss or reduces the charges.</string>
    <string name="supportGroupsQuestion2">What is InterNations?</string>
    <string name="supportGroupsAnswer2"><a href="http://www.internations.org">InterNations</a> is a social networking site for foreigners and ex-pats. The website is free to use and lets you create a profile similar to Facebook and connect with others. You can participate in events, groups, and forums to meet other travelers or immigrants from around the world in person or online.</string>
    <string name="tubeButton">Watch</string>
    <string name="youTubeInstructions">Click on the forward and back buttons to scroll to other videos on the playlist.</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalQuestion1">How can I find out more about Mexican consular services in the United States?</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalAnswer1"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mx.gob.sre.miconsulmex">MiConsúlmex</a> is an Android/iOS app for Mexicans living in the US. Through the app, you can find the nearest consulate, learn about recent immigration laws that affect you, and find information you should know about education, health and travel. It also includes links to SIRME where you can complete visa/birth/passport forms online. The app is free to download.</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu13">Mexican Nationals</string>
    <string name="adviceButton">Provide Advice</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Closed</string>
    <string name="facebook" translatable="false">Facebook</string>
    <string name="twitter" translatable="false">Twitter</string>
    <string name="website">Website</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion15">I want to apply for an H-1B visa. What are some tips for me?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer15">An H-1B visa allows employees with specialized skills in a particular field as well as a bachelor’s degree to pursue full- or part-time work in the US. Any company can sponsor an H-1B visa as long as it can demonstrate it can pay the salary of the sponsored employee. The cost is between $1575 for a company with less than 25 FT employees and $2325 for a company with 25 or more FT employees. These are the fees for regular processing which can take months at present, so premium processing is required for quick decision and this costs an additional $1125. To improve your chances, consider the following: Many petitions are rejected because the paperwork was improperly completed or submitted. In addition, you should pursue premium processing.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer16">"No, you do not have to stay with the same company for at least six months. If your intent at the time of application was to stay with the company and your company’s intent was to keep you employed in that role, then you can leave at any time.  "</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion16">I have a green card through my sponsor employer but I want to leave. Do I have to stay for at least six months before leaving the company?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion17">What are the criteria for an EB-1A visa and how many of them do I need to satisfy?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer17">You need to meet at least three of the ten criteria (the full list is <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/eir/visa-guide/eb-1-extraordinary-ability/understanding-eb-1-requirements-extraordinary-ability">here</a>). However, even if you meet the three criteria requirement you still need to demonstrate “extraordinary ability” but in practice all applicants with three criteria met will be approved. The entire process can take between three and eight months.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion18">I work for a foreign company owned by a US company. How can I immigrate to the US?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer18">You may be able to apply for an L-1 transferee visa that allows a US employer to transfer an executive or manager from a foreign affiliate office to its US office. It also allows companies without a US office to send a manager to the US to open one as long as the employee is doing or will do business in the US. The duration of the visa is one to three years. Although it’s easier for employees of large multinational “blanket” companies, you can still receive one if you work at a small company if you meet the criteria. However, you may need to back up your application with more substantial documentation in this case.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion19">I do not have a university degree. Can I still receive a work visa?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer19">Yes, a formal university education is not a prerequisite for a visa to work in the US. If you have significant and exceptional work experience you can apply for an H-1B or even O-1 visa to work in the US.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion20">How much should I invest to receive an E-2 visa? How much of it should be spent in the US before I apply?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer20">In general, you want to spend over $100,000 to qualify for this visa. This money should be raised from you or other investors in your country. The lower the dollar amount you invest, though, the more of it you need to prove you have spent in the US before you submit your E-2 application. So for a $100,000 investment, you should prove you have spent nearly all of it.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion21">What is a U visa and do I qualify?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer21">A U Visa is a non-immigrant visa that grants status to victims of crimes such as human trafficking, domestic violence, sexual assault, mental abuse, or other crimes. Individuals who have been harmed can apply for themselves and their families to receive this visa, and the U Visa requires recipients to cooperate with the police investigating the crimes committed. It lets you live in the country for four years. You can apply inside or outside the US, including while held in an immigration detention center. <a href="https://www.ilrc.org/sites/default/files/resources/proseuvisamanual_english.pdf">This guide</a> can help you through the application process.</string>
    <string name="visaHelpQuestion22">What is credible fear and does it apply to me?</string>
    <string name="visaHelpAnswer22">In the US, a person cannot be subject to deportation if he or she has a “credible fear” of persecution due to race, religion, etc., or torture after returning home. If you are detained by border officials and processed for expedited deportation, you can request a credible fear interview with an Asylum Official. You will then present your case before an Immigration Judge who can grant a deferral of removal.  Afterward, you may apply for asylum from the detention facility or after you are released on bond. You should be honest and detailed in your initial interview, because if you add details in later hearings with other officials it may be held against you. The government will provide a lawyer at no cost upon request.</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalQuestion2">What is a TN visa and how can I apply?</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalQuestion3">What is AccesoLatino and how can it help me?</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalAnswer2">The TN visa is a non-immigrant NAFTA Professional visa. NAFTA is a free trade agreement among the US, Canada, and Mexico. It grants a certain number of visas for professionals working in <a href="http://www.nafsa.org/_/file/_/amresource/8cfr2146.htm">these professions</a> from Mexico to work in the US. To receive this visa, you must complete <a href="https://ceac.state.gov/genniv/">Form DS-160</a> and schedule an interview. The fee is $160 per application.</string>
    <string name="mexicanNationalAnswer3"><a href="http://accesolatino.org/">AccesoLatino</a> is a website created by the Carlos Slim Foundation to assist Mexicans coming to the US. It provides career, English, driver’s license, and naturalization help. You can watch videos, browse job training sites, find resources for learning English, and find Latin American  consulates in the US.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion6">How can I send money back to my home country?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer6">You have many options for sending money to your home country, and each provider offers advantages over the others. In general, cash-to-cash transfers cost far more than bank-to-bank transfers. Sending money online, however, may take longer to arrive. There are many hidden costs when transferring money overseas so it’s important to compare the companies that offer these services.
        \n\n•<a href="https://transferwise.com/us/">TransferWise</a> is the cheapest option for sending money to Mexico is well-regarded for its quality of service.The cost per transfer varies based on the dollar amount, but it uses a fair, public exchange rate for everytransaction.
        \n\n•<a href="https://www.westernunion.com/">WesternUnion</a> is one of the cheapest options because of its competitive exchange rates. For cash pickup, there are over 26,000 WesternUnion locations across Mexico. In addition, there is no fee if you send up to $2750 online or via the WesternUnion app to a bank account in Mexico. In-person transfers with cash pickup arrive within  minutes.
        \n\n•<a href="https://www.remitly.com/us/en/">Remitly</a> has both low costs and many locations in Mexico. The exchange rates are competitive, and transfers are free if you pay with a bank account. A debit card transfer, meanwhile, costs $4.
        \n\n•<a href="https://www.riamoneytransfer.com/en-us">Ria</a> has the largest network of pickup locations in Mexico. It costs $3 to cover a transfer from a bank account or $4 with a debit card regardless of the amount. Transfers from debit or credit cards arrive within minutes while transfers from bank accounts can take up to five days.</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpQuestion10">What is voluntary departure and why should I care?</string>
    <string name="deportationHelpAnswer10">Voluntary departure provides some benefits over deportation if you are detained. If you choose to return to your home country voluntary, the Department of Homeland Security will not put a removal order on you. In this case, you avoid deportation. You can request to leave voluntarily while in removal proceedings before the hearing, while in Immigration Court, and even after the proceedings if you are about to be deported. Your immigration record stays clean since you will not receive a deportation order, so you will not automatically be prevented from returning the US legally in the future.  In addition, you are required to leave the country within 60 or 120 days, so you will have time to take care of your affairs.</string>
    <string name="error">Error</string>
    <string name="newsfeed">Newsfeed</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="blog_article_image">Blog article image</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion1">I do not have DACA. Should I apply for it now?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion2">I already have DACA. Should I apply to renew my DACA?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion3">What will happen to DACA under the next administration?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion4">What will happen to the information on DACA applications?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion5">If my DACA is terminated, will I be able to work?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion6">I have DACA and want to travel outside the United States. Is it safe to travel?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion7">If I an undocumented and think I may be eligible for an immigration benefit, should I apply now?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion8">I am undocumented and I have a U.S. citizen child. Is there anything I can do to protect myself?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion9">What are my rights if ICE stops me in the street or my house?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion10">Where am I safe from ICE enforcement actions?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion11">How can the community report any ICE activities in violation of these policies?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion12">Is it safe for me to protest and march in rallies?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion13">What are sanctuary cities?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformQuestion14">What will happen to sanctuary policies under the next administration?</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer1">If you do not currently have DACA, we recommend that you not file at this time. No one is certain at this time about what will happen with DACA. Given the legitimate fears about what will happen to immigrants under a new administration, we recommend not submitting a first-time application for DACA until we see what happens next year.\n\nEven for those who may still be considering applying for DACA for the first time, it is unlikely that your application will be processed before January 20, 2017 (when the new administration takes over), since it can take over three months to process a DACA application. By then, the DACA program may have been terminated. There is no guarantee that you will have your application or the filing fee (which is currently $465 and will go up to $495 starting on December 23, 2016) returned to you.\n\nWe don’t know what will happen next year, but you can, in the meantime, still gather supporting documents and prepare your application, in case the DACA program is not terminated.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer2">If you already have DACA, there is less risk in submitting a renewal application, since immigration authorities already have the information on your original application. If you have a criminal arrest, charge or conviction, or have traveled outside the U.S. without permission, there may be additional risks if you apply for renewal.\n\nHowever, it is possible that if you apply for renewal now, your application may not be approved before the Trump administration begins on January 20, 2017. There is also no guarantee that the $465 ($495 starting December 23, 2016) application fee will be returned to you.\n\nGiven the uncertainty over the future of DACA, if you plan to renew, it is best to apply right away, even if your employment authorization is not set to expire until late next year. Currently, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) is taking anywhere from 8 weeks to 120 days to process and approve DACA renewal applications.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer3">We will need to wait until next year to see what the next administration will do, but it has strongly indicated that it very much intends to terminate DACA soon after the new administration takes over on January 20, 2017. If the DACA program is terminated, it is not clear how it will treat DACA and work permits that have been issued but have not yet expired. One possibility is that it may decide to revoke all DACA recipients’ DACA and work permits immediately. Another possibility is that it may allow people to keep their DACA and work permits until they expire, but just not allow DACA recipients to renew them.\n\nIf the new administration allows the DACA program to end simply by not renewing DACA applications, and if you are able renew your DACA before the new administration stops processing renewal applications, you may have DACA for an additional two years. During that time, you would have authorization to be employed and also protection from deportation.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer4">Currently, USCIS’s policy is that it does not share information about a DACA applicant or the applicant’s family members with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) for immigration enforcement purposes unless there are serious criminal, fraud, or national security issues with the case. This policy is based on a 2011 USCIS memo which states that USCIS will refer to ICE only cases that raise fraud or “egregious public safety” concerns (such as that the applicant has a serious criminal conviction). Changing these policies would require that USCIS change its memo and guidance.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer5">Under federal law, your employer is required to reverify your employment authorization document (EAD) no later than the date that your EAD expires. It is likely that your employer will ask you for proof that your employment authorization has been renewed and will ask you to complete section 3 of the I-9 form to show that you presented an EAD with a new expiration date.\n\nIf, on the date your EAD expires, you cannot present proof that you have employment authorization, your employer may decide they can no longer employ you. If your EAD has expired, you are not obligated to tell your employer that this has happened, but you will be at risk of being fired when your employer realizes that your EAD has expired.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer6">If you have DACA and want to continue living in the U.S., you should never travel abroad unless you have applied for and received advance parole from USCIS. Advance parole is permission from USCIS to return to the U.S. after traveling abroad.\n\nIf you are planning a trip abroad—and if you receive advance parole—you should return to the U.S. as quickly as possible, by early January 2017, and no later than January 20, 2017. Even if you’ve received advance parole, you may not be permitted back in the country after January 20, 2017.\n\nIf you have not yet applied for advance parole, you can apply, but it may be too late to get a decision before January 20, 2017. There is no guarantee that you will have your application or the filing fee (which is currently $360 and will go up to $575 starting on December 23, 2016) returned to you. If you have an emergency, it may be possible to get a decision faster. Check with a qualified legal representative right away before you decide to apply.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer7">Yes, you should go to a legal services provider who can screen you for any possible immigration options for which you may be eligible. Some resources that will help you find legal help are:\n\n· The immigration courts’ list of lawyers and organizations that <a href="http://www.justice.gov/eoir/list-pro-bono-legal-service-providers-map">provide free legal services</a>.\n\n· At <a href="https://www.adminrelief.org">this site</a>, there’s a search engine that allows you to type in a zip code and get a list of all the legal services near you.\n\n· American Immigration Lawyers Association’s <a href="http://www.ailalawyer.com">online directory</a>.\n\n· iAmerica for an <a href="http://iamerica.org/find-legal-help">online list</a> of legal services by state.\n\n· Immigration Advocates Network’s national directory of more than 950 free or low cost nonprofit <a href="https://www.immigrationlawhelp.org">immigration legal services providers</a> in all 50 states.\n\n· Immigrant Legal Resource Center has a comprehensive online client <a href="https://www.ilrc.org/screening-immigration-relief-client-intake-form-and-notes">intake form</a>.\n\n· National Immigrant Justice Center allows you to schedule a legal consultation by phone +13126601370 or email (immigrantlegaldefense@heartlandalliance.org).\n\n· National Immigration Project of the National Lawyers Guild’s online find-a-lawyer <a href="https://www.nationalimmigrationproject.org/find.html">tool</a>.\n\n· United We Dream’s hotline: +18443631423.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer8">It is important to create a safety plan if you are worried about any interaction with ICE or possible detention or deportation. These are some steps you can take:\n\n· Memorize the phone number of a friend, family member, or attorney that you can call if you are arrested.\n\n· Make a plan to have your children or other loved ones looked after if you are detained.\n\n· Women’s Refugee Commission has resources specifically for parents at risk of family separation: <a href="https://www.womensrefugeecommission.org/rights/gbv/resources/1031-make-a-plan-migrant-parents-guide-to-preventing-family-separation-english">Make A Plan: Migrant Parents Guide to Preventing Family Separation</a> and <a href="https://www.womensrefugeecommission.org/rights/gbv/resources/1022-detained-or-deported-parental-toolkit-english-interactive">Detained or Deported: What About My Children? Parental Toolkit</a>\n\n· Keep important documents such as birth certificates and immigration documents in a safe place where a friend or family member can access them if necessary, or provide them with copies of these documents for safe-keeping.\n\n· Make sure your loved ones know how to find you if you are detained by ICE. They can use ICE’s <a href="https://locator.ice.gov/odls/homePage.do">online detainee locator</a> to find an adult who is in immigration custody. Or they can call the <a href="https://www.ice.gov/contact/ero">local ICE office</a>. Make sure they have your alien registration number written down, if you have one.\n\nThese are all resources you can trust, but you should always be aware of fraudulent service providers. For community education flyers to protect yourself against immigration service provider fraud, go to <a href=" https://www.ilrc.org/anti-fraud-flyers">this site</a>.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer9">You have rights guaranteed under the U.S. Constitution. There are many organizations that have created Know Your Rights resources available in English and other languages, including:\n\n· <a href="https://www.aclu.org/know-your-rights?topics=270">American Civil Liberties Union (English and Spanish)</a>\n\n· <a href="http://www.immdefense.org/ice-home-and-community-arrests//">Immigrant Defense Project</a>a (English and Spanish) · <a href="https://www.nilc.org/issues/immigration-enforcement/everyone-has-certain-basic-rights/">National Immigration Law Center</a> · <a href="http://iamerica.org/know-your-rights">iAmerica for Know Your Rights infographics</a> (Spanish and English) · <a href="https://www.nationalimmigrationproject.org/iceWatch.html">National Immigration Project of the National Lawyers Guild</a></string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer10">DHS policy instructs immigration and border agents to avoid conducting enforcement actions at sensitive locations (however, there are some exceptions). While these policies may change under a new administration, locations covered by these policies include:\n\n· Schools, such as known and licensed daycares, pre-schools and other early learning programs; primary schools; secondary schools; post-secondary schools up to and including colleges and universities; as well as scholastic or education-related activities or events, and school bus stops that are marked and/or known to the officer, during periods when school children are present at the stop;\n\n· Medical treatment and health care facilities, such as hospitals, doctors’ offices, accredited health clinics, and emergent or urgent care facilities;\n\n· Places of worship, such as churches, synagogues, mosques, and temples;\n\n· Religious or civil ceremonies or observances, such as funerals and weddings; and\n\n· During public demonstration, such as a march, rally, or parade.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer11">To report an enforcement action that you believe is in violation of ICE policy, contact:\n\n· ICE Enforcement and Removal Operations (ERO) by phone (through the Detention Reporting and Information Line at +18883514024), by email (ERO.INFO@ice.dhs.gov) or <a href="https://www.ice.gov/webform/ero-contact-form">online</a>.\n\n· The Civil Liberties Division of the ICE Office of Diversity and Civil Rights may be contacted at +12027320092 or ICE.Civil.Liberties@ice.dhs.gov.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer12">The First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution prohibits the government from restricting your right to free speech. This means that anyone in the U.S., regardless of their immigration status, has the right to participate in political protests, marches, and demonstrations.\n\nHowever, it is important that you assess the risks of any potential interaction with law enforcement and to avoid arrest by local, state or federal law enforcement under any circumstances. Before you decide whether to participate in any such actions, it is important that you consult with an attorney.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer13">While there is no uniform definition, the term “sanctuary city” is often used to describe localities that limit the role of local police in enforcing federal immigration law, by prohibiting or limiting compliance with ICE detainers and requests for notification of a person’s release date from police custody. These policies have been adopted in over 400 communities across the U.S., because they make communities safer, protect individuals from violations of their constitutional rights, and ensure that ICE does not exceed its authority with improper arrests.\n\nAt a time of deeply fractured trust between law enforcement and local communities, particularly communities of color, these policies are widely embraced as one step towards restoring trust between immigrant and other community members who fear that interactions with local and state police could expose their loved ones to deportation.</string>
    <string name="immigrationReformAnswer14">Nothing in federal law that requires state or local police to comply with ICE detainers or otherwise do the job of federal immigration officials. As a result, cities across the country with some variation of a “sanctuary” policy, including Chicago, Los Angeles, New York, Philadelphia, San Francisco, Santa Fe, Seattle, and Washington, D.C. have publicly reaffirmed their commitment to their existing policies and have said they have no plans to change them under a new administration.</string>
    <string name="homepageMenu0">Emergency</string>
    <string name="emergencyQuestion1">What should I show to an ICE official at my door?</string>
    <string name="emergencyAnswer1" translatable="false">I do not wish to speak with you, answer your questions, or sign or hand you any documents based on my 5th Amendment rights under the United States Constitution.  I do not give you permission to enter my home based on my 4th Amendment rights under the United States Constitution unless you have a warrant to enter, signed by a judge or magistrate with my name on it that you slide under the door. I do not give you permission to search any of my belongings based on my 4th Amend rights.  I choose to exercise my constitutional rights.</string>
    <string name="emergencyQuestion2">What should I say or do if an ICE officer comes to my door?</string>
    <string name="emergencyAnswer2">You have constitutional rights.\n\nDO NOT OPEN THE DOOR IF AN IMMIGRATION SERVICE AGENT IS KNOCKING AT THE DOOR.\n\nDO NOT ANSWER ANY IMMIGRATION SERVICE AGENT QUESTION IF THEY TRY TO TALK TO YOU. You have the right to remain silent. You do not have to give your name to the agent. If you are at work, ask the agent if you are free to leave and if the agent says leave. You have the right to speak with an attorney. DELIVER THE ANSWER OF THE PREVIOUS QUESTION IN THIS SECTION TO THE AGENT. DO NOT OPEN DOOR.</string>
    <string name="emergencyQuestion3">Call Southern Poverty Law Center</string>
    <string name="emergencyQuestion4">Call United We Dream</string>
    <string name="emergencyAnswer3" translatable="false">+18884147752</string>
    <string name="emergencyAnswer4" translatable="false">+18443631423</string>
    <string name="disclaimer">This app is not a lawyer. Please consult an attorney for legal advice.</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="search">search</string>
    <string name="share">share</string>
    <string name="back">back</string>
    <string name="searchRequest">Search...</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion7">What is a FICO score?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer7">A FICO score is a credit score developed by Fair Isaac Corporation (FICO). It is widely recognized as an industry standard used by financial institutions to evaluate the creditworthiness of a potential borrower. FICO maintains an algorithm that pulls credit data collected by the three national credit bureaus (Equifax, Experian and TransUnion) and produces a single, three-digit score from each of the three credit bureaus. Most FICO scores range from 300 to 850. The higher the score the lower the credit risk.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion8">How does compound interest work?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer8">Compound interest is an interest that is applied to both the initial principal and the accumulated interests on the loan. Essentially, the interest earned each period is added to the principal, which allows you to earn a higher interest for the next period. Because the interest is “compounded”, the total balance not only grows, but grows exponentially.</string>
    <string name="financialQuestion9">What is a credit score and how can I build a strong rating for myself?</string>
    <string name="financialAnswer9" formatted="false">A credit score is a number that is based on an analysis of a person’s credit history, and is used by lenders to predict the default risk of a potential borrower. In the United States, a credit score is primarily based on credit reports produced by the three major credit bureaus: Equifax, Experian and TransUnion. There are different algorithms to calculate credit scores, FICO score developed by Fair Isaac Corporation is one of the most popular scores used by lenders.
        \n\nIn order to build a strong credit rating, it is important to understand what types of data are used to calculate the score. A FIFO score is based on the following five categories of information, each with a weight assigned to reflect the importance of the factor.
        \n\n• Payment history (35\%%)
        \n\n• Amounts owed (30\%%)
        \n\n• Length of credit history (15\%%)
        \n\n• Credit mix (10\%%)
        \n\n• New credit (10\%%)
        \n\nThere are a number of ways to build a strong credit rating, however, most take time. Hence it is important to manage it overtime.
        \n\n• Apply for a credit card. This is the easiest and quickest way to establish a credit profile.
        \n\n• Pay your bills on time and every time. This is the most important of part of building and maintaining a good credit score.
        \n\n• Keep the balance low. The credit score takes into account of how likely you would reach your credit card limit. Hence it is better to keep the balance low relative to the total credit limit. It is often advised to keep the balance under 30% of the limit. If you happen to go beyond 30%, a trick is to pay it down before the balance is reported to the credit bureau, usually on the statement closing date.
        \n\n• Having a long credit history. The longer (and better) credit history you have, the more data/evidence there is for the credit bureau to establish your good credit rating.
        \n\n• Having a variety of credit products. Other things equal, a portfolio of different credit products, such as a mortgage, an auto loan and a credit card will produce a higher score than having just a credit card.
        \n\n• Do not apply for a lot of credit over a short period of time. This contributes to the “new credit” component. Opening several credit accounts over a short period of time represents a greater risk. Because it may appear that you are experiencing liquidity issues.</string>
</resources>
